# **GUSTAVO ALONSO SALAZAR HUAMAN**

Mechatronic Engineer | Full stack developer | Le Wagon graduate | Ruby on Rails | Javascript® Vue®

**+51 941455221** 

@ qslazar96@qmail.com

Phttps://www.linkedin.com/in/gustavo-alonso-salazar-huaman-4a1494168/

Peru



### **EXPERIENCE**

### Technical asistant

#### **FLSmidth**

**m** 03/2024 - 09/2024

Company Description

- Corrective maintenance of rod and ball mills
- Overhaul of primary crusher
- seal replacement
- corrective maintenance of HPGR.
- Programmed in Ruby, Python, and Ruby on Rails.
- Using Stimulus for frontend interactivity
- Implementing Geocode API integrations
- Worked with Mustache templates and various APIs in projects.

### Engineering assistant

#### **ENERGIA PERU S.A.C.**

**m** 05/2023 - 09/2023 Areguipa, Perú

Company Description

- Design of mechanical and electrical plans for steam lines and machine components for mining and food industry companies, using Microsoft Access and SQL databases.
- Design of plans for thermal machines, heat exchangers, and boilers.
- Supervise and program electrical panels for purge lines, preventive and predictive maintenance of steam equipment and steam lines.
- Measurement of electrical lines, grounding systems, and quality reports to clients once maintenance is completed, with expertise in HTML, CSS, and JavaScript for web development.

### Customer service

#### **Teleperformance**

**=** 03/2022 - 09/2022 Arequipa, Perú

Company Description

- Provided customer service support to individuals in the United States, efficiently resolving various customer service issues and inquiries, ensuring a high level of satisfaction.
- Expertly managed problem-solving for international clients, utilizing advanced soft skills and fluency in the English language to communicate effectively in real-time, particularly in high-pressure and stressful situations.
- Demonstrated proficiency in the use of Microsoft Excel, including complex data analysis, and Microsoft Access for database management, while also automating tasks and improving workflow efficiency through the development and implementation of VBA macros.

### **Engineering Assistant**

### **CONSTRUCCIONES RUBAU**

Company Description

- Supervised the construction and installation of grounding mesh and grounding pits, ensuring compliance with quality protocols through detailed inspection and measurement tests to meet industry standards.
- Managed the construction and installation of duct banks, as well as the power and instrumentation wiring, ensuring optimal performance and safety.
- Applied advanced machine learning and deep learning techniques using Python, Keras, and Jupyter notebooks to optimize project management, data analysis, and predictive maintenance.
- Leveraged neural networks for predictive modeling, allowing for early detection of potential issues in electrical systems and improving overall efficiency and decision-making processes in construction and maintenance tasks.

### SUMMARY

Hello! I am a developer specialist in Ruby, Python, Angular lover who loves to test himself with projects, APIS, documentation I love reading learning and challenge myself every single day I have C1 level english and I have bachelor degreee in Mechatronics engineering and Le Wagon graduate with knowledge in databases, scopes and of course soft skills.

### **LANGUAGES**

# Chinese Beginner **English** Native **Portuguese** Advanced

### **EXPERIENCE**

# Instrumentation and Electrical Intern at a Concentrator SOUTHERN PERU COPPER CORPORATION

Company Description

- Maintenance of frequency inverters, feeder belt motors, electric belt motors, screen motors, main flotation motors, hydraulic unit motors, cleaning belt motors, crusher motors, fan motors, and the hydraulic system of copper filter presses.
- Maintenance of hopper level instruments, plate feeders, scales, belts, screens, hydrocyclones, air intake instruments, and level control in flotation cells, hydraulic units for crushers, and instrument calibration.
- Maintenance and lubrication of ball mills, rod mills, SAG mills, including electrical and instrumentation work, with a focus on applying machine learning techniques such as clustering using Python, and dust detection systems developed with Python and OpenCV.

### **Auxiliary Fleet Maintenance Intern**

#### **SOUTHERN PERU COPPER CORPORATION**

Company Description

- Creation of maintenance work orders, generation of reservations, notifications, and preventive maintenance, as well as technical closures for auxiliary fleet.
- Support in preventive maintenance at 250, 500, 1000, and 2000 hours for auxiliary fleet in the tractor workshop.
- Creation of daily work logs and management of backlog control.

### **EDUCATION**

### Full stack developer IT

Le Wagon

**=** 07/2024 - 10/2024

# Deep Learning with Python and Keras, artificial inteligence

**Universidad Peruana Cayetano Heredia** 

**=** 01/2021 - 12/2021

## Bachelor degree in Mechatronic engineering

Universidad Católica de Santa María

**=** 01/2014 - 12/2019

# Machine Learning with Python

**Universidad Peruana Cayetano Heredia** 

**=** 01/2021 - 12/2021

### **Backend Developer**

Coderhouse

**=** 08/2022 - 01/2023